<Answer findings_version="1" findings_type="LLR">
  <Justification>
    <FindingID>LLR--1--1</FindingID>
    <Explanation>The LL refinement coverage for HL-EXPL-1.2 was missing. Without a Low-Level Requirement refining HL-EXPL-1.2, traceability from high-level exploration behavior to implementable functionality is incomplete. A new LL requirement LL-EXPL-1.4 is proposed to close this gap and provide concrete wall-detection reliability and map integration capabilities.</Explanation>
  </Justification>
  <Implementation>
    <FindingID>LLR--1--1</FindingID>
    <Solution><![CDATA[
<Requirement ID="LL-EXPL-1.4">
  <Type>FR</Type>
  <Name>Wall detection reliability</Name>
  <Relationships>
    <Refines>HL-EXPL-1.2</Refines>
    <DependsOn>LL-EXPL-1.2</DependsOn>
  </Relationships>
  <Content>Robot shall reliably detect walls under varying sensor noise conditions and integrate detections into the occupancy map to avoid collisions during exploration.</Content>
</Requirement>
]]></Solution>
  </Implementation>

  <Justification>
    <FindingID>LLR--1--2</FindingID>
    <Explanation>The High-Level Requirement HL-MAP-2.2 contains a typographical error in its Name ("Cell Clasification"). This creates inconsistency in naming across traceability, reviews, and tooling. The issue is informational/editorial and should be corrected to maintain documentation quality and traceability.</Explanation>
  </Justification>
  <Implementation>
    <FindingID>LLR--1--2</FindingID>
    <Solution><![CDATA[
Rename High-Level Requirement HL-MAP-2.2 Name from "Cell Clasification" to "Cell Classification".
Impact: Update all references to HL-MAP-2.2 in Low-Level Requirements and any tooling that consumes the HL names. No functional behavior changes required.
]]></Solution>
  </Implementation>

  <Justification>
    <FindingID>LLR--1--3</FindingID>
    <Explanation>Localization and Pose Estimation capability is not explicitly covered by any Low-Level Requirement, yet it is essential to support exploration and mapping operations (pose updates influence mapping, planning, and execution). The gap could hinder architecture-level design and integration testing. A new Low-Level Requirement LL-LOC-7.1 is proposed to address this functional gap.</Explanation>
  </Justification>
  <Implementation>
    <FindingID>LLR--1--3</FindingID>
    <Solution><![CDATA[
<Requirement ID="LL-LOC-7.1">
  <Type>FR</Type>
  <Name>Localization and Pose Estimation</Name>
  <Relationships>
    <Refines>HL-EXPL-1.1</Refines>
    <DependsOn>LL-EXPL-1.2</DependsOn>
    <DependsOn>LL-MAP-2.1</DependsOn>
  </Relationships>
  <Content>Robot shall estimate its pose in the environment using sensor fusion and provide pose with uncertainty; Pose updates shall be integrated into the map and planning modules; The system shall expose pose estimates with timestamp and support pose quality metrics (e.g., covariance) for downstream modules.</Content>
</Requirement>
]]></Solution>
  </Implementation>
</Answer>