<Findings version="9" source="LLR" source_version="9">
  <Finding id="LLR--9--1">
    <ItemID>LL-UNKNOWN-9.0</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>Low Level Requirements document LL-9.xml content was not provided. Without LL9 content, we cannot verify refinements, dependencies, or traceability (including interaction with LL-LOC-7.1) and naming consistency.</Description>
    <Solution>Provide the LL-9.xml content (or paste its contents), ensuring that LL-9.x requirements exist, refine the appropriate HL requirements, and declare necessary DependsOn relationships. After delivery, a formal Answer document with Findings, Justifications, and Implementations will be generated, and full traceability verification including LL-LOC-7.1 interactions and naming propagation will be performed.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--9--2">
    <ItemID>HL-MAP-2.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>High-Level Requirement HL-MAP-2.2 currently uses the misspelled name "Cell Clasification". This spelling discrepancy affects traceability, reviews, and tooling consistency across HL and LL documents.</Description>
    <Solution>Rename HL-MAP-2.2 to "Cell Classification" and propagate the corrected name to all references and tooling. Ensure LL-MAP-2.2 aligns with the corrected HL name, updating any LL references if necessary.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--9--3">
    <ItemID>LL-LOC-7.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>LL-LOC-7.1 currently contains potential redundancy by combining a DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.1 with a Refines HL-EXPL-1.1. This can create an ambiguous traceability path or cyclical dependency if further LL-EXPL changes are introduced.</Description>
    <Solution>Update LL-LOC-7.1 Relationships to remove the DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.1 and keep a single, clean trace to HL/LL prerequisites. Recommended final relationships: Refines HL-EXPL-1.1; DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.2; DependsOn LL-INTERF-6.1; DependsOn LL-MAP-2.1. Provide an updated LL-LOC-7.1 snippet reflecting this change.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--9--4">
    <ItemID>HL-MAP-2.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>Consistency between HL and LL naming for Cell Classification should be maintained. HL currently uses a misspelled name, which can propagate inconsistencies into LL mappings and traceability tooling.</Description>
    <Solution>Align HL naming with LL by renaming HL- MAP-2.2 to "Cell Classification" and ensure all LL references (e.g., LL-MAP-2.2) are updated to reflect this corrected term. Validate traceability mappings from HL to LL after the change.</Solution>
  </Finding>
</Findings>