<Findings version="22" source="LLR" source_version="22">
  <Finding id="LLR--22--1">
    <ItemID>LL-22-PLACEHOLDER-1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>LL-22 content has not been provided. Without LL-22 content, we cannot verify refinements, dependencies, or traceability (including interactions with LL-LOC-7.1).</Description>
    <Solution>Provide LL-22.xml contents (or paste its requirements) so LL-22 refinements, dependencies, and traceability can be verified. After receipt, generate the full Findings/Implementations document for LL-22 and perform complete traceability validation, including LL-LOC-7.1 interactions.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--22--2">
    <ItemID>HL-MAP-2.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>High-Level Requirement HL-MAP-2.2 uses the historical misspelling "Cell Clasification" in some references. This affects traceability, reviews, and tooling consistency across HL and LL documents. The current practice should be to consistently use "Cell Classification" across both levels.</Description>
    <Solution>Rename HL-MAP-2.2 to "Cell Classification" in the HL document if not already corrected, propagate the corrected name to all references, and ensure LL-MAP-2.2 aligns with the corrected HL name. Validate end-to-end traceability HL <-> LL for this requirement.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--22--3">
    <ItemID>LL-LOC-7.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>LL-LOC-7.1 shows potential redundancy by having a DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.1 alongside a Refines HL-EXPL-1.1. This can create an ambiguous traceability path or cycles if further LL-EXPL changes are introduced.</Description>
    <Solution>Harmonize LL-LOC-7.1 traceability to a single coherent pattern. Recommended: Refines HL-EXPL-1.1; DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.2; DependsOn LL-INTERF-6.1; DependsOn LL-MAP-2.1. Remove any redundant LL-EXPL-1.1 from LL-LOC-7.1 to maintain an acyclic, unambiguous traceability graph.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--22--4">
    <ItemID>HL-PLAN-3.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Moderate</Severity>
    <Description>LL-PLAN-3.2 references HL-PLAN-3.2, but the HL document currently does not define HL-PLAN-3.2. This creates a mismatch in traceability between LL-PLAN-3.2 and the HL plan set.</Description>
    <Solution>If HL-PLAN-3.2 is not defined in the HL requirements, either add HL-PLAN-3.2 to the HL document and refine LL-PLAN-3.2 to reference it, or adjust LL-PLAN-3.2 to refine only HL-PLAN-3.1. Ensure consistent traceability for all LL-PLAN-3.x items.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--22--5">
    <ItemID>HL-INTERF-6.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>To maintain consistency, ensure that HL-INTERF-6.1 and LL-INTERF-6.1 mapping remain in sync when sensor data interfaces evolve. Current LL-INTERF-6.1 refines HL-INTERF-6.1; verify ongoing alignment.</Description>
    <Solution>Review evolution of HL-INTERF-6.1 and maintain LL-INTERF-6.1 alignment. If HL-INTERF-6.1 changes, propagate to LL-INTERF-6.1 and adjust dependent LL requirements accordingly; re-run traceability checks.</Solution>
  </Finding>
</Findings>