<Findings version="6" source="LLR" source_version="6">
  <Finding id="LLR--6--1">
    <ItemID>LL-UNKNOWN-6.0</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>Low Level Requirements document LL-6.xml content was not provided. Without LL6 content, we cannot verify refinements to HL requirements, dependency graphs, or traceability (including potential interactions with LL-LOC-7.1 and existing HL/LL mappings).</Description>
    <Solution>Provide the Low Level Requirements document LL-6.xml (or paste its contents), ensuring that LL-6.1..LL-6.x exist and refine the appropriate HL requirements (e.g., HL-EXPL-1.1, HL-MAP-2.1/2.2, HL-PLAN-3.1, HL-INTERF-6.1/6.2) and declare necessary DependsOn relationships. After delivery, I will produce the corresponding Findings, Justifications, and Implementations in a formal Answer document.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--6--2">
    <ItemID>LL-LOC-7.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>Preliminary review of prior findings indicates that if LL-LOC-7.1 introduces new cross-references or dependencies in LL6, there is a risk of creating circular or ambiguous traceability. A dedicated verification pass for LL-LOC-7.1 must be performed after LL-6 content is provided to ensure an acyclic, properly refined trace from LL to HL.</Description>
    <Solution>Once LL-6 content is available, validate LL-LOC-7.1’s refinements and dependencies to ensure there is a single, clear path to HL-EXPL-1.1, and that no new circular dependencies are introduced. If needed, adjust LL-LOC-7.1 to keep a clean, acyclic graph (e.g., keep Refines HL-EXPL-1.1 and ensure DependsOn only to LL-EXPL-1.2, LL-INTERF-6.1, LL-MAP-2.1).</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--6--3">
    <ItemID>HL-MAP-2.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>There remains a misspelling in the High-Level Requirement HL-MAP-2.2: "Cell Clasification" should be "Cell Classification". This spelling discrepancy affects traceability, review, and tooling consistency across HL and LL documents.</Description>
    <Solution>Correct HL-MAP-2.2 to "Cell Classification" in the HL document and propagate the corrected name to all references in LL documents and tooling. Ensure all LL requirements that refer to HL-MAP-2.2 align with the corrected name (e.g., LL-MAP-2.2 name changed to "Cell Classification").</Solution>
  </Finding>
</Findings>