<Findings version="2" source="LLR" source_version="2">
  <Finding ID="LLR--2--1">
    <ItemID>LL-MAP-1.4.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>
LL-MAP-1.4.2 allows wall segment states {UNKNOWN, PRESENT, ABSENT} and explicitly permits updating these values “as observations confirm or refute” the presence of walls. In contrast, LL-MAP-1.3.5 states that once-observed wall and free classifications are immutable for the duration of a mission and LL-MAP-1.4.1 restricts transitions for cells to UNKNOWN→FREE/BLOCKED only, never back to UNKNOWN. There is no corresponding constraint for wall segments, so the phrase “as observations confirm or refute” implies reversible changes (e.g., PRESENT↔ABSENT) that contradict the static-map assumption for walls and create ambiguity about allowed state transitions.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Align wall-segment transition rules with the static map assumption by refining LL-MAP-1.4.2, e.g.:
- Either restrict transitions analogously to cells (UNKNOWN→PRESENT or UNKNOWN→ABSENT only; no changes once set during a mission), and state this explicitly, or
- If dynamic wall changes are intentionally allowed, relax LL-MAP-1.3.5 and specify clear transition rules for both cells and walls, and update HL--ENV--2.1/HL--MAP--1.3 refinement to reflect a non-static map.
In either case, ensure that state-transition constraints for walls are explicitly defined and consistent with LL-MAP-1.3.5.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR--2--2">
    <ItemID>LL-MAP-1.1.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
LL-MAP-1.1.1 depends on LL-RUN-1.1.1 (Return Path Computation), but the content of the requirement states that “In the RETURN_TO_START state, the state machine shall request computation of a path...”, indicating that the mission control state machine initiates the return path, while LL-RUN-1.1.1 currently states that the return module initiates computation upon receiving EXPLORATION_* events. This creates ambiguity about which component is the active initiator and how responsibilities are split between mission control and the return module.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Clarify and make consistent the initiation flow:
- Either define LL-RUN-1.1.1 as a service/API that mission control calls from the RETURN_TO_START state (and update its wording accordingly), or
- Define mission control as a subscriber to EXPLORATION_* events that transitions into RETURN_TO_START while the return module autonomously starts path computation.
Update LL-MAP-1.1.1 and LL-RUN-1.1.1 so that a single, unambiguous initiation mechanism is described and the dependency direction is clear.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR--2--3">
    <ItemID>LL-EVENT-1.1.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
LL-EVENT-1.1.1 states that “The software shall publish events EXPLORATION_COMPLETED and EXPLORATION_TIMEOUT...” but does not specify which concrete module is responsible for publishing these events or how they are technically delivered (e.g., function callback, queue, flag). Although the publisher is implied to be “exploration and time-management modules”, the lack of explicit assignment and interface description makes integration with the mission control state machine and return module less clear from an architectural perspective.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Extend LL-EVENT-1.1.1 or add a linked requirement to:
- Explicitly designate the mission control state machine or a dedicated exploration-status module as the publisher of EXPLORATION_* events, and
- Define the event delivery mechanism at a behavioral level (e.g., “shall invoke registered callbacks”, “shall enqueue into a system event queue accessible to the mission control and return modules”).
This will clarify ownership and interaction patterns for these critical events.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR--2--4">
    <ItemID>LL-SCHED-1.1.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
LL-SCHED-1.1.1 defines a periodic control loop with configurable period T corresponding to the sensor sampling rate, while LL-RELIAB-1.2.1 separately defines the sensor sampling rate range [10, 50] Hz and default 20 Hz. It is implied but not explicitly stated that T shall be the inverse of this sampling rate, and that there is a single coherent rate for both control-loop execution and sensor sampling. This implicit coupling can lead to inconsistent interpretations (e.g., different rates for control and sampling).
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Explicitly relate T to the sensor sampling rate, for example by refining either LL-SCHED-1.1.1 or LL-RELIAB-1.2.1 to state:
- “The control-loop period T shall be chosen such that the control loop executes at the same rate as the sensor sampling rate defined in LL-RELIAB-1.2.1.”
or
- “The sensor abstraction layer shall sample sensors once per control-loop iteration as defined in LL-SCHED-1.1.1.”
This ensures consistent timing assumptions for architecture and implementation.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR--2--5">
    <ItemID>LL-RELIAB-1.2.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
LL-RELIAB-1.2.2 introduces “at least N configurable consecutive sensor readings” as the condition to change an established wall or cell classification but does not define bounds, default, or recommended value for N. Without any constraints on N, the system behavior can become either too conservative (never updating) or too reactive (effectively N = 1), making it hard to reason about reliability and performance at architecture level.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Add constraints for N in LL-RELIAB-1.2.2 or a dedicated parameter requirement, e.g.:
- Specify that N is a configurable integer ≥ 2 with a documented default (e.g., N_default = 3), or
- Provide a recommended range (e.g., 2 ≤ N ≤ 10) and state that modules depending on this mechanism shall use this range.
This will improve testability and make the noise-handling behavior more predictable.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR--2--6">
    <ItemID>LL-INTERF-1.2.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
LL-INTERF-1.2.1 specifies that motor_set is “invoked at a configurable control loop frequency that does not exceed a specified maximum update rate consistent with the periodic control loop” but does not define where or how this maximum update rate is specified (no referenced parameter requirement) nor its relation to the sensor/control-loop frequency. This leaves a gap for architects regarding allowable command rates and their configuration.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Introduce either:
- A new requirement defining the maximum allowable motor command update rate (e.g., a hardware/interface constraint requirement under HARDWARE or INTERF category), or
- Extend LL-SCHED-1.1.1 to state that motor_set is called at most once per control-loop iteration.
Then reference that requirement from LL-INTERF-1.2.1 so the limit is explicit and traceable.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR--2--7">
    <ItemID>LL-POSE-1.1.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
LL-POSE-1.1.1 states that pose is updated “in each control loop cycle based on differential drive kinematics and motion commands” but does not specify how absolute time (duration of commands) is obtained, even though LL-HARDWARE-2.1.1 mentions “control-loop timing.” The dependency from LL-POSE-1.1.1 to LL-SCHED-1.1.1 is present, but the requirement itself does not explicitly require using the control-loop period T to integrate kinematics, which may lead to underspecified timing usage in the pose module.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Clarify LL-POSE-1.1.1 to explicitly state that:
- The pose update shall use the control-loop period T (or measured cycle duration) from LL-SCHED-1.1.1 when integrating differential-drive kinematics.
This ties pose estimation clearly to the scheduling model and makes the timing dependency explicit in the content, not just in the relationships.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR--2--8">
    <ItemID>LL-MAP-1.3.7</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
LL-MAP-1.3.7 defines a grid map access interface with query and update functions and an event mechanism “by which other modules can be notified when specific cells or walls change classification” but does not specify whether map access is thread-safe or in which execution context these callbacks/events are invoked relative to the periodic control loop. For architecture, especially if concurrency or interrupt-driven callbacks are used, this lack of execution-context specification can lead to inconsistent assumptions.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Augment LL-MAP-1.3.7 to specify that:
- Map access (queries/updates) and classification-change events occur within the context of the periodic control loop (single-threaded) or
- If an asynchronous/event-driven model is intended, specify that callbacks shall not pre-empt map updates or must use synchronization/queuing mechanisms.
Even a high-level statement about execution context will support more robust architectural decisions.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR--2--9">
    <ItemID>LL-MAP-1.1.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
LL-MAP-1.1.2 states that the mission control state machine shall enter EXPLORE “after completion of all initialization routines”, but no LLR defines what constitutes completion of initialization nor which module signals this. This is a system-level precondition that directly affects when exploration can start, but without an explicit initialization-completion requirement or signal, the behavior remains partly implicit.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Add a small requirement under INTERF, HARDWARE, or a SYSTEM/INIT category specifying:
- That an initialization module shall signal an INIT_COMPLETED or equivalent flag/event once all required hardware and software initializations are done.
- That the mission control state machine shall only transition from IDLE to EXPLORE once this signal is set.
Then reference that requirement in LL-MAP-1.1.2 (via DependsOn) to close the loop.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR--2--10">
    <ItemID>Traceability-General</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
The identification pattern mandated by SRP ( {level}-{category}-{section}.{item} ) is not consistently followed across all LLR IDs. Examples:
- “LL-MAP-1.1.1” uses single hyphens rather than double hyphens as in HLR IDs (e.g., HL--MAP--1.1) and omits a dot in the section/item split.
- Some extra requirements use patterns like “LL-SCHED-1.1.1”, “LL-POSE-1.1.1” but HLRs use “HL--ENV--1.1” with a double hyphen after level and category.
While this is mostly cosmetic, inconsistent ID schemes can hinder automated traceability and violate the stated identification convention.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
Normalize LLR IDs to strictly follow the defined pattern and be consistent with HLRs, e.g.:
- Use “LL--MAP--1.1.1” (double hyphens) if that is the intended style, or
- Update SRP or both HLR/LLR sets to a consistent variant.
The key is to ensure a single, documented pattern and apply it uniformly to all requirement IDs.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>
</Findings>