<Findings version="15" source="LLR" source_version="15">
  <Finding id="LLR--15--1">
    <ItemID>LL-15-PLACEHOLDER-1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>LL-15 content has not been provided. Without LL-15 content, we cannot verify refinements, dependencies, or traceability (including interactions with LL-LOC-7.1).</Description>
    <Solution>Provide LL-15.xml contents (or paste its requirements) so LL-15 refinements, dependencies, and traceability can be verified. After receipt, generate the full Findings/Implementations document for LL-15 and perform complete traceability validation, including LL-LOC-7.1 interactions.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--15--2">
    <ItemID>HL-MAP-2.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>HL-MAP-2.2 uses the misspelled name "Cell Clasification". This spelling discrepancy affects traceability, reviews, and tooling consistency across HL and LL documents.</Description>
    <Solution>Rename HL-MAP-2.2 to "Cell Classification" and propagate the corrected name to all references; ensure LL-MAP-2.2 aligns with corrected HL name and update dependent LL references accordingly.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--15--3">
    <ItemID>LL-LOC-7.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>LL-LOC-7.1 shows potential redundancy by having a DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.1 alongside a Refines HL-EXPL-1.1. This can create an ambiguous traceability path or cycles if further LL-EXPL changes occur.</Description>
    <Solution>Maintain a single trace mechanism. Recommended: Refines HL-EXPL-1.1; DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.2; DependsOn LL-INTERF-6.1; DependsOn LL-MAP-2.1. Remove LL-EXPL-1.1 from DependsOn if present in the current relationships; update LL-LOC-7.1 accordingly.</Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--15--4">
    <ItemID>HL-MAP-2.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>Consistency between HL and LL naming for Cell Classification should be maintained. HL currently uses a misspelled name, which can propagate inconsistencies into LL mappings and traceability tooling.</Description>
    <Solution>Rename HL-MAP-2.2 to "Cell Classification" and propagate this corrected term to LL references (e.g., LL-MAP-2.2). Validate traceability mappings from HL to LL after the change.</Solution>
  </Finding>
</Findings>