<Findings version="21" source="LLR" source_version="21">
  <Finding id="LLR--21--1">
    <ItemID>LL-20-PLACEHOLDER-1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>LL-20 content has not been provided. Without LL-20 content, we cannot verify refinements, dependencies, or traceability (including interactions with LL-LOC-7.1).</Description>
    <Solution><![CDATA[
<Requirement ID="LL-20-PLACEHOLDER-1">
  <Type>FR</Type>
  <Name>Placeholder for LL-20 content</Name>
  <Relationships/>
  <Content>LL-20 content to be provided by you. This placeholder exists to document that LL-20 analysis cannot proceed until LL-20 content is available.</Content>
</Requirement>
]]></Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--21--2">
    <ItemID>HL-MAP-2.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>High-Level Requirement HL-MAP-2.2 uses the misspelled name "Cell Clasification" in some historical references. This spelling discrepancy affects traceability, reviews, and tooling consistency across HL and LL documents. The current correction in the latest HL should be propagated to LL references.</Description>
    <Solution><![CDATA[
Rename HL-MAP-2.2 to "Cell Classification" in the HL document if not already corrected, and propagate the corrected name to all references.
In LL, ensure LL-MAP-2.2 corresponds to the corrected HL name (Cell Classification). Update any dependent LL references accordingly and validate end-to-end traceability HL <-> LL for this requirement.
]]></Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--21--3">
    <ItemID>LL-LOC-7.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>LL-LOC-7.1 shows potential redundancy by having a DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.1 alongside a Refines HL-EXPL-1.1. This can create an ambiguous traceability path or cycles if further LL-EXPL changes are introduced.</Description>
    <Solution><![CDATA[
Harmonize LL-LOC-7.1 traceability to a single coherent pattern. Recommended: Refines HL-EXPL-1.1; DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.2; DependsOn LL-INTERF-6.1; DependsOn LL-MAP-2.1. Remove any redundant DependsOn LL-EXPL-1.1 from LL-LOC-7.1 and adjust relationships accordingly to maintain an acyclic traceability graph.
]]></Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding id="LLR--21--4">
    <ItemID>HL-MAP-2.2</ItemID>
    <Severity>Moderate</Severity>
    <Description>Consistency between HL and LL naming for Cell Classification should be maintained across both documents to prevent future traceability issues.</Description>
    <Solution><![CDATA[
If HL-MAP-2.2 is confirmed corrected to "Cell Classification" in the HL document, propagate the change to LL as LL-MAP-2.2 and verify traceability HL->LL. Update any tooling or references accordingly.
]]></Solution>
  </Finding>
</Findings>