<Findings version="1" source="LLR" source_version="4">
  <Finding ID="LLR--4--1">
    <ItemID>Answer-Justification-HL-EXPL-1.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Catastrophic</Severity>
    <Description>
      HL-EXPL-1.1 in the HLR document remains a structurally invalid requirement:
      - It still uses a combined type value &quot;NFR / FR&quot;, which violates SRP 3.3 (a requirement must be either FR or NFR).
      - It is not testable or implementable as a system capability (&quot;Example&quot; with &quot;Example Description&quot;).
      - It is not refined by any LLR, violating SRP 3.1.1(5) (&quot;High-level requirements must be refined by at least one Low-level requirement.&quot;)
      The Answer document justifies leaving HL-EXPL-1.1 unchanged on the grounds that HLR modification is out of scope for the LLR update; however, the SRP defines properties on the overall requirements set, not per-layer independently. Keeping HL-EXPL-1.1 as a formal HLR while knowingly non-conformant leaves the High Level Design phase invalid. This affects the entire requirements baseline and therefore the downstream LLRs and Architecture Design, qualifying as a catastrophic process issue.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
      Roll back to the High Level Design phase and correct HL-EXPL-1.1 before proceeding:
      1) Either remove HL-EXPL-1.1 from the HLR XML entirely and relocate any explanatory material to non-requirement documentation; or
      2) Convert HL-EXPL-1.1 into a valid NFR:
         - Assign a single valid type attribute (e.g., type=&quot;NFR&quot;).
         - Rewrite &lt;Name&gt; and &lt;Content&gt; to describe a clear, testable, implementable requirement (for example, a requirement on the requirements documentation or process).
         - Provide at least one corresponding LLR that refines it, ensuring no contradictions.
      Only after the HLR set conforms to SRP (all HLRs are valid and refined) should the LLR set and architecture design be considered stable. A dedicated Findings/Answer cycle for the HLR document is required.
    </Solution>
    <RollbackPhase>High Level Design</RollbackPhase>
  </Finding>
</Findings>