<Findings version="1" source="LLR_Answer" source_version="3">
  <Finding ID="LLR_Answer--3--1">
    <ItemID>Answer-Root</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>
      The &lt;Answer&gt; document does not follow the specified Answer Document Structure in the SFP. According to the policy:
      - The root tag must have attributes &quot;findings_version&quot; and &quot;findings_type&quot; (the example also shows only these two).
      - Each &lt;Implementation&gt; and &lt;Justification&gt; must contain a &lt;FindingID&gt; and an &lt;Explanation&gt; child.
      In the provided Answer:
      - The root tag is &lt;Answer findings_version=&quot;1&quot; findings_type=&quot;LLR_Answer&quot;&gt; (correct attributes) but
      - Each &lt;Implementation&gt; and &lt;Justification&gt; uses a &lt;Content&gt; child instead of the required &lt;Explanation&gt; tag.
      This violates the defined Answer structure and will cause schema/non-conformance issues for tools.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
      Rename the &lt;Content&gt; child in every &lt;Implementation&gt; and &lt;Justification&gt; block to &lt;Explanation&gt; so that each has the form:
      &lt;Implementation&gt;
        &lt;FindingID&gt;...&lt;/FindingID&gt;
        &lt;Explanation&gt;...&lt;/Explanation&gt;
      &lt;/Implementation&gt;
      and similarly for &lt;Justification&gt;. Keep the root attributes as they are.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR_Answer--3--2">
    <ItemID>HL-EXPL-1.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Major</Severity>
    <Description>
      High-level requirement HL-EXPL-1.1 remains unchanged with:
      - &lt;Type&gt;NFR / FR&lt;/Type&gt; (combined type, violating SRP 3.3 which requires a single type FR or NFR), and
      - Example-style name and content that are not clearly implementable or testable.
      The Answer document provides a Justification that HL-EXPL-1.1 is merely an example and outside the scope of LLR changes, and it avoids refining it in the LLRs. However:
      - SRP 3.1.1(5) still requires that all HLRs be refined by at least one LLR if they are part of the formal HLR set.
      - Keeping HL-EXPL-1.1 inside the HLR document as a normal &lt;Requirement&gt; while declaring it &quot;just an example&quot; in the Answer creates a process inconsistency: consumers of the HLR XML cannot distinguish it from real system requirements.
      The Justification is therefore incomplete: it acknowledges the issue but does not resolve the structural non-conformance in the requirements set.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
      Perform a separate HLR revision to bring HL-EXPL-1.1 into conformance. Options:
      a) Remove HL-EXPL-1.1 from the HLR XML entirely and move any explanatory text to a non-requirements section; or
      b) Retain HL-EXPL-1.1 but:
         - Set its type attribute to a single valid value (e.g., type=&quot;NFR&quot;),
         - Rewrite its &lt;Name&gt; and &lt;Content&gt; to describe a concrete, testable requirement (e.g., on the requirements documentation process), and
         - Provide at least one LLR that refines it.
      Until such a change is made, the HLR set formally violates the SRP. This should be tracked in a findings document for the HLRs themselves.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR_Answer--3--3">
    <ItemID>LLR-IDs</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
      The LLR IDs have been improved but still do not fully follow the SRP 3.2 pattern &quot;{level}-{category}-{section}.{item}&quot;:
      - {level} and {category} are used correctly (e.g., LL-EXPL, LL-MAP, LL-PLAN).
      - However, several IDs use patterns like &quot;LL-EXPL-1.1&quot; to &quot;LL-EXPL-1.5&quot; and &quot;LL-EXPL-2.1&quot; to &quot;LL-EXPL-2.5&quot;. This is acceptable as long as &quot;section&quot; is taken as &quot;1&quot; or &quot;2&quot; and &quot;item&quot; as the second digit.
      The earlier finding asked to ensure only one dotted &quot;section.item&quot; structure and a clear category code. That condition is now met. However, in some categories there is only one section (e.g., LL-PLAN-2.1) which may make &quot;section&quot; semantics slightly unclear but does not violate the pattern itself.
      This is a minor observation: structurally, the IDs are now conformant enough for traceability, but the interpretation of &quot;section&quot; is somewhat ad hoc across categories.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
      Document the chosen mapping from functional groupings to &quot;section&quot; numbers in a short convention note (for internal process use), e.g., &quot;Section 1 = core functions; Section 2 = time constraints or components&quot;. No XML changes are strictly required for SRP conformance at this point.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR_Answer--3--4">
    <ItemID>LL-PLAN-1.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
      LL-PLAN-1.1 content now reads:
      &quot;The system shall compute paths as sequences of adjacent FREE cells ..., treating BLOCKED and UNCERTAIN cells as non-traversable in all modes, and treating UNKNOWN cells as non-traversable for planned optimal runs including the second run; all controllers, including reactive collision-avoidance behaviors, shall only command motion within FREE cells and may enter UNKNOWN cells only by following paths planned according to LL-PLAN-1.2.&quot;
      While this addresses the previous ambiguity, the sentence is long and combines two distinct concerns:
      - Path-planning rules (how UNKNOWN, BLOCKED, UNCERTAIN are treated),
      - Controller constraints (which cells controllers may step into).
      This slightly reduces clarity and may complicate test decomposition, because it mixes planning rules and controller behavior in a single requirement.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
      Optionally split LL-PLAN-1.1 into two requirements:
      - One focusing on the path-planning semantics (traversable vs. non-traversable cell types).
      - One focusing on controller behavior regarding which cell types may be entered and under what conditions (referencing LL-PLAN-1.2).
      This is an improvement suggestion rather than a strict SRP violation; if you prefer to keep a single requirement, no change is mandatory.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR_Answer--3--5">
    <ItemID>LL-RUN-1.2 / LL-RUN-3.1</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
      LL-RUN-1.2 and LL-RUN-3.1 now both:
      - Refine HL-PLAN-3.1 and
      - Depend on LL-PLAN-2.1 (Optimal Path Planner component),
      which is good and resolves the earlier ambiguity. However, the DependsOn relationships reference an LLR in the same layer. SRP 2.1.2 allows DependsOn for both HL and LL relationships and states only that a requirement that refines another cannot depend on it. LL-RUN-1.2/3.1 do not refine LL-PLAN-2.1, so this is valid.
      There is a minor documentation risk: the Answer text describes these relationships, but the LLR XML only shows &lt;DependsOn&gt;LL-PLAN-2.1&lt;/DependsOn&gt; without any explicit semantics (e.g., that the planner must be initialized/available). The dependency is therefore purely structural and leaves concrete timing/initialization aspects to design.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
      If stronger guidance to architecture is desired, consider adding to LL-PLAN-2.1 or the RUN requirements a sentence such as: &quot;The Optimal Path Planner component shall be initialized and available before any Return-to-Start or Second-Run phase is initiated.&quot; This would make the operational dependency explicit; it is not required for SRP compliance but could improve design guidance.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>

  <Finding ID="LLR_Answer--3--6">
    <ItemID>LL-INTERF-2.3</ItemID>
    <Severity>Minor</Severity>
    <Description>
      LL-INTERF-2.3 now includes a validation requirement:
      &quot;... the system shall provide configuration validation that rejects any combination ... that would make it impossible to traverse the maximum maze size defined in LL-MAP-1.1 within the mapping time constraint defined in LL-MAP-2.1 under nominal conditions.&quot;
      However, &quot;nominal conditions&quot; are referenced indirectly via LL-MAP-2.1, which defines them in terms of maze size, dead-end percentage, reference hardware, and absence of faults. This is acceptable, but the wording &quot;under nominal conditions&quot; in LL-INTERF-2.3 is slightly redundant/implicit and may cause testers to look for a local definition in LL-INTERF-2.3 itself.
    </Description>
    <Solution>
      Optionally clarify by explicitly referencing LL-MAP-2.1 in the text, e.g., &quot;... under nominal conditions as defined in LL-MAP-2.1&quot;. This will remove any residual ambiguity about where &quot;nominal conditions&quot; are specified. The requirement is otherwise sound and testable.
    </Solution>
  </Finding>
</Findings>